Hans Hofmann
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Photographs, circa 1925-1966, undated, Series 6:; (Boxes 9-10; 1.25 linear ft.; Reel 5809)
  Photographs are of people, events, places, works of art, and miscellaneous subjects. Within these categories, photographs are organized into the subjects indicated by the folder titles listed below. Each folder is arranged chronologically; 35-mm color slides and negatives have not been microfilmed. Oversize photographs are of people and works of art; these items are stored and microfilmed together, and appropriate cross references are provided.
  Photographs of people include Hofmann alone, with Miz, with students and others. They are mostly undated and are arranged in rough chronological order. Among the pictures of Hans and Miz Hofmann are several of them wearing oriental costumes, circa 1920s. Those of Hofmann with students and others are mostly unidentified (the one exception is a view labeled "Fred Hauck, Janet Chase, Herr Hofmann, Warren Cheney, Molly Bennett at Upper Angora Lake above Lake Tahoe, California, August, 1930;" in the folder titled "Hans Hofmann with Others"); several photographs in this category are over or under exposed, obscuring faces. A small leather album stamped with the title "Snap Shots Hancock, N.Y." contains 15 photographs of Hans, Miz, students, and friends. Photographs of identified individuals are Georg Hampton, Effie Bell Rogers, and Cornelia Ryder; only first names are provided for the few group shots that are identified.
  Photographs of events record some of the "Forum 49" events held at Gallery 200 include Fritz Bultman, Adolph Gottlieb, Hemley, Hans Hofmann, Weldon Kees, Karl Knaths, Blanche Lazell, and Judith Rothschild. Exhibition installation views and photographs of openings are of the Venice Biennale, 1960; Galerie im Künstlerhaus, Munich, 1962; Museum of Modern Art, "Recent Acquisitions: Painting and Sculpture," 1966; and an unidentified exhibition in Germany, undated Also documented are ceremonies at which Hofmann was awarded honorary degrees: University of California, Berkeley, 1964, includes many views with Glenn and Kay Wessels, and Monica and John Haley at the San Francisco airport; and Pratt Institute Founder's Day, 1965.
  Many of Hofmann's paintings are visible in the photographs of places. Views of Hofmann's New York studio, 1966, include paintings and images of Renate Schmitz Hofmann. Travel pictures are of Italy, Mexico, California[?], and unidentified locations.
  Photographs of works by Hans Hofmann include the New York School of Printing mural, and "Summer" and "Rhapsody" from his Renate series. Also part of this subseries are Renate Schmitz Hofmann's 1974 gift of 313 35-mm color slides of paintaings executed between 1935 and 1965. Other artists are Detre, Georg Hampton, M. Wolfegg Hofmann, Sterling Poindexter, Myron S. Stout, L. Vivin (represented in Hofmann's personal art collection), Glenn Wessels, and Fritz Winter. Teaching materials are photographs of Old Masters paintings, drawings, and Classical sculpture, some marked to indicate line, form, or proportion; many are stamped "staatlich genehigt, Schule für bildende Kunst, Hans Hofmann, München."
  Oversize photographs include portraits of Hofmann by Sid Grossman, Arnold Newman, Irving Penn, and Leon Schnall; Miz was photographed by Ruth Jacobi-Roth and Marvin Lazarus. With the exception of a nude study by Lee Krasner, student works are unidentified.
  This series is divided into 6 subseries:
  6.1: People, 1920s-1965, undated
  6.2: Events, 1949-1966
  6.3: Places, 1920s-1967, undated
  6.4: Works of Art, 1930-1965, undated
  6.5: Miscellaneous Subjects, 1941-1948
  6.6: Oversize, 1940-1965, undated
  - People, 1920s-1965, undated, 6.1:
    - Hans Hofmann (See also: Box 10), 1920s-1965 (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Hans and Maria ("Miz") Hofmann, 1920s-1963 (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Hans Hofmann with Students/Students, 1920s-1950s (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Hans Hofmann with Others (See also: Box 10), 1920s-1964 (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Maria ("Miz") Wolfegg Hofmann (See also: Box 10), 1920s-1963 (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Maria ("Miz") Wolfegg Hofmann with Others, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Renate Schmitz Hofmann, 1965, undated (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Hofmann, Hans-Theo (nephew) and Family, 1947-1965, undated (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Photograph Album, circa 1930s-1960s (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Individuals, A-Z, 1929-1951, undated (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Unidentified Individuals, Adults, 1941, 1957, undated (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Unidentified Individuals, Children, 1935-1936, undated (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Groups (See also: Box 10), 1951, undated (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Unidentified Groups (Box 9, Reel 5809)
      - Adults, undated (Box 9, Reel 5809)
      - Families?/Adults with Children, undated (Box 9, Reel 5809)
      - Children, 1926-1927, 1950, undated (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Artist's Model, undated (Box 9, Reel 5809)
  - Events, 1949-1966, 6.2:
    - "Forum 49" at Gallery 200, 1949 (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Exhibitions, 1960-1966, undated (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Honorary Degrees, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Reel 5809)
  - Places, 1920s-1967, undated, 6.3:
    - Miz's Munich Apartment, circa 1935 (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Provincetown House, Interior and Exterior, 1958, undated (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Provincetown School, Exterior, 1941, undated (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Studio, 1966 (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Travel Pictures, 1920s, 1960s, undated (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Munich, circa 1935 (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Unidentified, 1965, undated (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Unidentified Houses, undated (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - University Art Museum, Berkeley, Calif., Architect's Model, 1967 (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - New York School of Printing (See: Oversize) (Box 9, Reel 5809)
  - Works of Art, 1930-1965, undated, 6.4:
    - By Hans Hofmann, 1935-1965, (1 folder, 2 slide boxes) (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - By Other Artists, D-W and unidentified, 1934-1937, undated, (6 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - By Unidentified Hofmann Students (See also: Oversize), 1930-1965, undated, (3 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Teaching Materials, undated, (3 folders) (Box 9, Reel 5809)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1941-1948, 6.5:
    - Dog, Cat, Dolls, 1941, undated (Box 9, Reel 5809)
    - Cover Design for Search for the Real in the Visual Arts (Glass Plate Negative), circa 1948 (Box 9, Reel 5809)
  - Oversize, 1940-1965, undated, 6.6:
    - Hans Hofmann, 1950s-1965 (Box 10 (sol), Reel 5809)
    - Hans Hofmann with Others, circa 1960 (Box 10 (sol), Reel 5809)
    - Maria ("Miz") Wolfegg Hofmann, 1957-circa 1962 (Box 10 (sol), Reel 5809)
    - Unidentified Individuals, 1940, undated (Box 10 (sol), Reel 5809)
    - Works of Art by Hofmann Students, undated (Box 10 (sol), Reel 5809)
    - New York School of Printing, Architects' Presentation Panel, 1956 (Box 10 (sol), Reel 5809)
- Printed Matter, 1930-1978, undated, Series 7:; (Boxes 11-16; 5.25 linear ft.; Reels 5809-5811)
  Printed Matter by Hans Hofmann is segregated; items by other authors are categorized by type, with each division arranged chronologically.
  Printed Matter By Hans Hofmann contains "Plastic Creation," 1932; Search for the Real and Other Essays, 1948; "The Color Problem in Pure Painting-Its Creative Origin," 1956; "Hawthorne-The Painter: An Appreciation," 1960 (in Hawthorne on Painting; From Students' Notes Collected by Mrs. Charles Hawthorne) and 1962 (in Charles W. Hawthorne, 1872-1930, Shore Galleries, Boston); "A Tribute to Adelyn D. Breeskin," 1962 (in the Baltimore Museum of Art News, summer 1962); statement on the work of Edith Sachs, undated (printed in announcement for her show, Feb. 23-March 8, Zodiac Gallery, New York); and an undated letter to the editor of Look.
  Exhibition Catalogs and Related Items concerning artists other than Hofmann have not been microfilmed.
  Miscellaneous printed matter includes a wide variety of items. An auction catalog for a fundraising event includes a Hofmann painting donated by the artist. University Art Museum: A Center for Cultural Study [UC, Berkeley], undated is a prospectus that shows models and drawings of the building and the location of its Maria and Hans Hofmann Wing. The scrapbook contains clippings, mainly exhibition reviews, and a small number of catalogs, checklists and invitations. Also included are two undated statements: "A Statement to the Public: Who Broke the Birds Nest?" by The Independent Advancing Artists, and "Aesthetic Realism: A General Statement."
  7.1: By Hans Hofmann, 1932-1962, undated
  7.2: Exhibition Catalogs and Related Items, 1931-1978, undated
  7.3: Newspaper Clippings, 1930-1974, undated
  7.4: Articles from Periodicals, 1928-1971, undated
  7.5: Miscellaneous Printed Matter, 1936-1965, undated
  7.6: Books Mentioning/About Hofmann, 1934-1963, undated
  - By Hans Hofmann, 1932-1962, undated, 7.1:
    - Articles, Essays, Letter to the Editor, 1932-1962, undated (Box 11, Reel 5809)
  - Exhibition Catalogs and Related Items, 1931-1978, undated, 7.2:
    - Hoffman, 7.2.1:
      - Solo and Group Exhibitions, 1931-1961, undated, (17 folders) (Box 11, Reel 5809-5810)
      - Solo and Group Exhibitions, 1962-1978, undated, (15 folders) (Box 12, Reel 5810-5811)
    - Other Artists, Solo Exhibitions, 7.2.2:
      - A-Z by Artist, undated, (16 folders) (Box 13, Reel unfilmed)
    - Other Artists, Group Exhibitions, 7.2.3:
      - A-Z by exhibition title, undated, (5 folders) (Box 13, Reel unfilmed)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1930-1974, undated, 7.3:
    - About or Mentioning Hofmann, 1930-1974, undated, (5 folders) (Box 14, Reel 5811)
    - About or Mentioning Hofmann, cont'd., 1930-1974, undated (Box 14, Reel 5811)
    - Art-related Topics1930-1969, undated, (4 folders) (Box 14, Reel unfilmed)
    - Miscellaneous Subjects, undated (Box 14, Reel 5811, Reel unfilmed)
  - Articles from Periodicals, 1928-1971, undated, 7.4:
    - About or Mentioning Hofmann, 1932-1971, undated, (8 folders) (Box 14, Reel 5811)
    - Art-related Topics, 1928-1966, undated, (7 folders) (Box 14, Reel unfilmed)
    - Miscellaneous Subjects, 1960, 1963, undated (Box 14, Reel unfilmed)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Matter, 1936-1965, undated, 7.5:
    - Art Courses (not Hans Hofmann School), 1936, 1963 (Box 14, Reel unfilmed)
    - Auction Catalog, 1 2th Annual Art Auction of the United Jewish Appeal of Greater New York, Parke-Bernet Galleries, Inc., 1965 (Box 14, Reel unfilmed)
    - Book Catalog and Prospectuses, 1951, 1961, undated (Box 14, Reel unfilmed)
    - Catalogs of Lamps, Paints, Art Supplies, circa 1960s (Box 14, Reel unfilmed)
    - Picture Post Cards, undated (Box 14, Reel unfilmed)
    - Provincetown Zoning By-Laws, 1957 (Box 14, Reel unfilmed)
    - Provincetown-Boston Airline Schedule, 1964 (Box 14, Reel unfilmed)
    - Reproductions of Works of Art by Hofmann and Others (See also: Box 16), undated (Reel unfilmed, Box 14)
    - Scrapbook (See: Box 16), 1944-1962 (Box 14, Reel unfilmed)
    - Statements, undated (Box 14, Reel unfilmed)
    - University Art Museum: A Center for Cultural Study, circa 1960s (Box 14, Reel unfilmed)
  - Books Mentioning or About Hofmann, 1934-1963, undated, 7.6:
    - Crotty, Frank. Provincetown Profiles and Others on Cape Cod. Barre, MA: Barre Gazette, 1958. (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - Claus, Jürgen. T heorien zeitgenössischer Malerei. Hamburg: Rowohlt Taschenbuch Verlag GmbH, 1963. (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - Cheney, Sheldon. Expressionism in Art. New York: Liveright Publishing Corp., 1934. (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - Eliot, Alexander. Three Hundred Years of American Painting. New York: Time Inc., 1957. (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - Geldzahler, Henry. American Painting in the 20th Century. New York: Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1965. (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - Greenberg, Clement. Hofmann. Paris: The Pocket Museum, Editions Georges Fall, 1961. (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - Guest, Barbara and B. H. Friedman. Goodnough. Paris: The Pocket Museum, Editions Georges Fall, 1962. (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - Hess, Thomas B. Abstract Painting. Background and American Phase. New York: Viking Press, 1951. (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - Janis, Sidney. Abstract & Surrealist Art in America. New York: Reynal & Hitchcock, 1944. (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - McDarrah, Fred W. The Artist's World in Pictures. New York: E. P. Dutton & Co., Inc., 1961. (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - Motherwell, Robert and Ad Reinhardt, eds. Modern Artists in America. First Series. New York: Wittenborn Schultz, Inc., [1951]. (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - Pousette-Dart, Nathaniel, ed. American Painting Today. A Cross-Section of Our Contemporary Art. New York: Hastings House, 1956. (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - Rathbun, Mary C. and Bartlett H. Hayes, Jr. Layman's Guide to Modern Art, Painting for a Scientific Age. New York: Oxford University Press, 1949. (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - Ritchie, Andrew Carnduff. Abstract Painting and Sculpture in America. New York: Museum of Modern Art, 1951. (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - Rosenberg, Harold. The Anxious Object. Art Today and its Audience. New York: Horizon Press, 1954. (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - Seitz, William C. Hans Hofmann; With Selected Writings by the Artist. New York: Museum of Modern Art, 1963. (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - Szittya, Emile. L'Art Allemand en France. Paris: Edition "La Zone," undated (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - Weller, Allen S. Art USA Now. Lucerne: C. J. Bucher, 1962. (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - Women. A Collaboration of Artists and Writers. New York: Samuel M. Kootz Editions, 1948. (Box 15, Reel unfilmed)
    - Oversize items, undated (Box 16 (sol), Reel unfilmed)
- Hans Hofmann Library, undated, Series 8:; (Boxes 16-19; 2.25 linear ft.)
  Books from Hans Hofmann's personal library were included among the papers donated to the Archives of American Art. Inscribed and annotated volumes have been retained with the collection. Art books have been separated from general literature, and each of these categories is boxed alphabetically as indicated below. A small selection of books by, about, or mentioning Hofmann are among the printed matter described in Series 8.
  All other books and periodicals (376 items) were transferred to the Library of the Smithsonian's American Art Museum, which retained relevant volumes, dispersed others to appropriate libraries within the Smithsonian Institution, and made final decisions regarding disposition of any remaining items.
  8.1: Inscribed/Annotated Volumes-Art, undated
  8.2: Inscribed/Annotated Volumes-General Literature, undated
  - Inscribed/Annotated Volumes-Art, undated, 8.1:
    - Oversize volumes, undated (Box 16 (sol), Reel unfilmed)
    - Art News Annual XXV, 1956. [annotated] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - L'Art Abstrait; ses origines; ses premiers maîgres. Paris: Maeght, 1949. [annotated] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Barr, Alfred H., Jr. Picasso; Fifty Years of his Art. New York: The Museum of Modern Art, 1946. [inscribed] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Bayl, Friedrich. Bilder unserer Tage. Koln: Verlag M. DuMont Schauberg, 1960. [inscribed] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Bazaine. Notes sur la peinture d'aujourd'hui. Paris: Floury, 1948. [inscribed] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Buttafava, G. and E. Garbagnati. Architetture nel segno dei Maestri. Bergamo, Italy: Instituto Italiano d'Arti Grafische, 1962. [inscribed] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Carnet de desseins de Picasso reproduits au format de l'original. Paris: "Cahiers d' Art," 1948. [inscribed] (See: Box 16) (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Clark, Kenneth. Landscape Painting. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1950. [inscribed] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Construction and Geometry in Painting; From Malevitch to "Tomorrow." New York: Galerie Chalette, 1960. [inscribed] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - The Edward Joseph Gallagher III Memorial Collection at the University of Arizona, Tucson. [1958]. [inscribed] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Gallatin, A. E., ed. Of Art; Plato to Picasso. New York: Wittenborn and Company, 1944. [inscribed] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Gary, Dorothy Hales and Robert Payne. The Splendors of Asia. New York: Viking Press, 1965. [inscribed] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Grabar, André. Byzantine Painting. New York: Skira Inc., 1953. [inscribed] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Graham, John D. System and Dialectics of Art. New York: Delphic Studios, [1937]. [annotated] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Hildenbrand, Adolf. Das Problem der Form in der Bildenden Kunst. Strassburg: J. H. Ed Heitz, 1901. [annotated] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Hunter, Sam. "Jackson Pollock: the Maze and the Minotaur." New World Writing. New York: New American Library, 1956. [annotated] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Jenkins. New York: Martha Jackson Gallery, 1965. [inscribed] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Kepes, Gyorgy. Language of Vision. Chicago: Paul Theobald, 1944. [annotated] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Malraux, André. The Voices of Silence. Garden City, NY: Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1953. [inscribed] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Modern Artists in America; First Series. Robert Motherwell and Ad Reinhardt, eds. New York: Wittenborn Schultz, Inc., [1951?]. [annotated] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Mondrian, Piet. Plastic Art and Pure Plastic Art, and Other Essays. New York: Wittenborn, Schultz, Inc., 1951. [inscribed] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Müller, Carl Theodor. Meister gotischer Plastit. München: J. S. Lehmanns Verlag, 1932. [inscribed] (Box 17, Reel unfilmed)
    - Nierendorf, Karl, ed. Paul Klee; Paintings, Watercolors, 1913-1939. New York: Oxford University Press, 1941. [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Pallottino, Massimo. Etruscan Painting. New York: Skira, 1952. [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - The Phillips Collection; a Museum of Modern art and its Sources; A Catalogue. New York and London: Thames and Hudson, 1952. [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Picasso; 32 peintures récentes. Paris: Cahiers d'Art, 1949. [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Regler, Gustav. Wolfgang Paalen. New York: Nierendorf Editions, 1946. [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Rembrandt Handzeighnungen. Leipzig: Im Insel Verlag, undated [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Rosenberg, Harold. Arshile Gorky; The Man, the Time, the Idea. New York: Horizon Press, Inc., 1962. [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Rosenberg, Harold. The Tradition of the Ne w. New York: Horizon Press, Inc., 1959. [inscribed and annotated] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Schön, Erhard. Unterweisung der Proportion und Stellung der Possen. [no place: undated] [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Seuphor, Michel. Écritures; Dessins/Drawings/Zeichnungen Alcopley. Paris: Les Nourritures Terrestres, 1954. [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Steinberg, Saul. The Catalogue. Cleveland and New York: World Publishing Co., 1962. [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Steinberg, Saul. The New World. New York: Harper & Row, 1965. [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Sweeney, James J. Joan Miró. New York: The Museum of Modern Art, 1941. [annotated] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Uhde, W. Picasso et la Tradition Française; Notes dur la Peinture Actuelle. Paris: Éditions des Quatre-Chemins, undated [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Valentiner, W. R. Origins of Modern Sculpture. New York: Wittenborn and Company, 1946. [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Walkowitz, Abraham. A Demonstration of Objective, Abstract, and Non-Objective Art. Girard, KS: Haldeman-Julius Publications, 1945. [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Walkowitz, Abraham. Isadora Duncan in Her Dances. Girard, KS: Haldeman-Julius Publications, 1945. [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Walkowitz, Abraham. 100 Paintings and Drawings from the Objective to Abstract. New York: B. W. Huebsch, Inc., 1925. [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Westheim, Paul. Indische Baukunst. Berlin: Verlag Ernst Wasmuth A. G., undated [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Woodward, William. French Quarter Etchings. New Orleans: Magnolia Press, undated [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
    - Wright, Frank Lloyd. The Future of Architecture. New York: Horizon Press, 1953. [inscribed] (Box 18, Reel unfilmed)
  - Inscribed/Annotated Volumes-General Literature, undated, 8.2:
    - Copley, Alfred Lewin and Helen Boswell. Aconite the Love Poison. Reprinted from Bulletin of the History of Medicine, Vol. XV, No. 4, April 1944. [inscribed] (Box 19, Reel unfilmed)
    - Einsichten. Freiburg, GER: Eberhard Albert Verlag, 1959. [inscribed] (Box 19, Reel unfilmed)
    - Graf, Oskar Maria. Unruhe um Einen Friedfertigen. New York: Aurora Verlag, 1947. [inscribed] (Box 19, Reel unfilmed)
    - Humphreys, Christmas. Buddhism. Hammondsworth, Middlesex, ENG: Penguin Books, 1952. [inscribed and annotated] (Box 19, Reel unfilmed)
    - Kant, Immanuel. Kritik der reinen Vernunft. Halle an der Saale, GER: Verlag von Otto Hendel, undated [annotated] (Box 19, Reel unfilmed)
    - Kuttner, Erich. Hans Von Marées; Die Tragödie des deutschen Idealismus. Zurich: Verlag Oprecht, 1937. [inscribed] (Box 19, Reel unfilmed)
    - Mann, Thomas. Doctor Faustus; The Life of the German Composer Adrian Leverkühn as Told by a Friend. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1948. [annotated] (Box 19, Reel unfilmed)
    - Neagoe, Peter. No Time for Tears. New York: Kamin Publishers, 1958. [inscribed] (Box 19, Reel unfilmed)
    - Ver Duft, Lee. Ho! Watchman of the Night, Ho! New York: Gemor Press, 1944. [inscribed] (Box 19, Reel unfilmed)
    - A World Treasury of Proverbs from Twenty-five Languages. Collected by Henry Davidoff. New York: Random House, 1946. [inscribed] (Box 19, Reel unfilmed)
- Estate of Hans Hofmann, 1945-1974, undated, Series 9:; (Box 19; 0.5 linear ft.; Reel 5811)
  Estate records are those of Robert Warshaw of Trubin, Sillcocks, Edelman & Knapp, Hofmann's attorney and co-executor. Material predating Hofmann's death are items collected to document the purchase of his Provincetown house, copies of records relating to the Estate of Maria Hofmann appended to legal documents filed on behalf of the Hans Hofmann Estate, and earlier tax records requested by the Internal Revenue Service for an audit of the 1965 tax return filed by the estate.
  Other tax records are filed with Financial Records (Series 4). Massachusetts estate tax records include some documents regarding the Estate of Maria Hofmann. Additional wills are among the biographical information with Miscellaneous Records (Series 5). Further information concerning the 1966 art theft is with the Papers of Renate Schmitz Hofmann (Series 10).
  This series is divided into 3 subseries:
  9.1: Taxes, 1962-1973, undated
  9.2: Provincetown House, 1945-1973
  9.3: Miscellaneous, 1965-1974
  - Taxes, 1962-1973, undated, 9.1:
    - Correspondence, 1966-1970 (Box 19, Reel unfilmed)
    - Tax Returns, 1962-1969 (Box 19, Reel unfilmed)
    - Supporting Documentation, 1962-1969, (6 folders) (Box 19, Reel unfilmed)
    - Massachusetts Estate Tax, 1966, 1973 (Box 19, Reel unfilmed)
    - New York Estate Tax, 1970-1971, undated (Box 19, Reel unfilmed)
    - Miscellaneous, 1965, 1972 (Box 19, Reel unfilmed)
  - Provincetown House, 1945-1973, 9.2:
    - Correspondence, 1966-1973 (Box 19, Reel 5811)
    - Inventories, 1972, undated (Box 19, Reel 5811)
    - Purchase and Ownership Records, 1945-1948 (Box 19, Reel 5811)
    - Sale, 1973 (Box 19, Reel 5811)
  - Miscellaneous, 1965-1974, 9.3:
    - Agreement between the University of California and Executors of the Estate of Hans Hofmann, 1971 (Box 19, Reel 5811)
    - Appraisal, 1967 (Box 19, Reel 5811)
    - Bank Statements, Accounting Records, 1965-1970, undated (Box 19, Reel unfilmed)